MUHAMMAD HAFIZH ASSHIDDIQY

muhammaddhafizhh16@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/muhammadhafizhasshiddiqy/

Pekanbaru, Riau

I am a fresh graduate from informatics engineering at islamic university of riau who is interested in software development. With my educational background, I understand technical concepts so I can easily solve technical and non-technical problems. I am adaptable and like to try and learn to gain new experiences and knowledge about the development of the technology world. I am interested in applying for software development projects. I believe that teamwork and communication are important roles in success and I am ready to immediately contribute to the team.

Work Experiences

Inatechno - Padang, Sumatera Barat

May 2023 - Oct 2023

Internship Software Developer

Inatechno is an IT Training Center institution and web, desktop and mobile-based information system creation & development services. Inatechno is located in the city of Padang, precisely on Jalan Marapalam Indah 5 no 12. Inatechno is the only IT Training Center institution that provides Android ATC international certification in Indonesia. This certification comes from Android ATC (Advanced Training Consultants) in Canada and is currently working with Inatechno. Inatechno itself has partnered training with ministries, stateowned enterprises and corporates.

- Take on the role of Software Developer in the development of sports digital products, from planning to testing stages.
- Take an active role in team collaboration during sports digital product development, ensuring a smooth development process.
- Filled the role of a Trainer with specialization in Flutter topics, ensuring the delivery of material to participants in a clear and effective
 manner.
- Played a key role in the sports digital product development team, demonstrating exceptional commitment and ability to meet development challenges.
- · Received appreciation from trainees for the ability to deliver Flutter material in an easy-to-understand and motivating manner.

Badan SAR Nasional - Pekanbaru, Riau

Feb 2021 - Mar 2021

Internship Web Developer

The Pekanbaru City Search and Rescue Agency (BASARNAS) is a dedicated organization responsible for conducting search and rescue operations within the jurisdiction of Riau. Committed to ensuring the safety and well-being of its residents, BASARNAS Pekanbaru is equipped with trained personnel and specialized equipment to respond promptly to emergencies, including natural disasters and accidents. Their swift and coordinated efforts play a vital role in safeguarding lives and property in the city.

- Played a key role as a Web Developer in the design and construction of an internal application for one of the divisions in Basarnas using PHP, HTML, and CSS technologies.
- Successfully developed and launched an internal application that met the needs and requirements of the division, significantly
 improving operational efficiency.
- Adapted guickly to changing needs and ensured the project was completed on time according to the set deadline.
- Received appreciation from the team and management for meaningful contributions in improving functionality and productivity within the Basarnas division.

Education Level

Universitas Islam Riau - Pekanbaru, Riau, Indonesia

Aug 2018 - Jun 2023

Bachelor Degree in informatics engineering, 3.90/4.00

- Developed a final project in the form of a credit application project using the Laravel framework to digitize the previously ineffective credit application process.
- Created a simple e-order project using Java to make it easier for customers to place orders.
- The credit application project successfully improved efficiency in the application process, eliminated barriers associated with conventional methods, and accelerated the approval process.
- The e-order project successfully provided a practical solution for customers, improved the ease of placing orders, and provided a more convenient and efficient experience in the transaction process.

Organisational Experience

Lembaga Adat Melayu Riau - Pekanbaru, Riau, Indonesia

Jun 2023 - Present

Anggota

Lembaga Adat Melayu Riau or LAM Riau, abbreviated as LAMR, is a regional customary institution initiated by Malay Riau figures from various backgrounds and professions, namely government officials, ulama, scientists / scholars from universities in Riau, culturists, artists, writers, and decent people who come from the traditional Malay Riau power environment.

• Play a role in designing and developing educational programs based on Malay cultural values.

• Contribute to the development of learning materials that promote and enrich the understanding of Malay culture. Provide assistance in digital development efforts to expand the reach and promote the richness of Malay culture.

Skills, Achievements & Other Experience

- Hard Skills ❷ (2023): Javascript Basic
- Hard Skills ❷ (2023): Creating a backend using Node Js for beginners
- Hard Skills ⊚ (2022): HTML certificate from Sololearn course
- Soft Skills: First Principles Thinking
- Soft Skills: Teamwork
- Soft Skills: Good Communication Skills
- Soft Skills: Adaptability
- Soft Skills: Collaboration Skills